The man. The myth. The movie.
Hercules is a animation, family, fantasy film directed by Ron Clements.
Bestowed with superhuman strength, a young mortal named Hercules sets out to
prove himself a hero in the eyes of his father, the great god Zeus.
Along with his friends Pegasus, a flying horse, and Phil, a personal trainer, Hercules is tricked by
the hilarious, hotheaded villain Hades, who's plotting to take over Mount Olympus!
Hercules (voice), played by Tate Donovan.
Young Hercules (voice), played by Josh Keaton.
Young Hercules (singing voice), played by Roger Bart.
Philoctetes (voice), played by Danny DeVito.
Hades (voice), played by James Woods.
Meg (voice), played by Susan Egan.
Hercules is a 1997 American animated musical fantasy comedy film loosely based on the legendary hero
Heracles (known in the film by his Roman name, Hercules), a son of Zeus in Greek mythology.
Produced by Walt Disney Feature Animation, the film was directed by John Musker and Ron Clements,
both of whom  co-wrote the screenplay with Donald McEnery, Bob Shaw, and Irene Mecchi.
Featuring the voices of Tate Donovan, Danny DeVito, James Woods, and Susan Egan, the film follows the titular Hercules, a demigod with super-strength raised among
mortals, who must learn to become a true hero in order to earn back his godhood and place in Mount Olympus, while his evil uncle Hades plots his downfall.
Development of Hercules began in 1992 following a pitch adaptation of
the Heracles mythological stories by animator Joe Haidar.
Meanwhile, Clements and Musker re-developed their idea for Treasure Planet (2002)
following the critical and commercial success of Aladdin (1992).
Their project was removed from development in 1993, and Musker
and Clements joined Hercules later that same year.
Following an unused treatment by Haidar, Clements and Musker studied multiple interpretations
of Greek mythology before abandoning Zeus's adulterous affair with Alcmene.
The project underwent multiple story treatments and a first script draft was inspired by the
screwball comedy films of the classic Hollywood era and popular culture of the 1990s.
During production, McEnery, Shaw, and Mecchi were brought on
board to revise Musker and Clements' script.
British cartoonist Gerald Scarfe was recruited as production designer and
produced over seven hundred visualization designs of the characters.
Research trips to Greece and Turkey provided
inspiration for the background designs.
Animation for the film was done in California and Paris.
Computer animation was used in several scenes,
predominantly in the Hydra battle sequence.
The production budget was $85 million.
Hercules was released on June 13, 1997, and received generally positive reviews from film critics, with James Woods's performance as
Hades receiving particular praise, but the animation (particularly the visual style) and music received a mixed response.
The film under-performed in its theatrical release notably in comparison to previous animated
Disney films, ultimately earning $252.7 million in box office revenue worldwide.
Hercules was later followed by Hercules: The Animated Series, a syndicated Disney television series focusing on Hercules during his time at the
Prometheus Academy, and the direct-to-video prequel Hercules: Zero to Hero (1999), which consists of four episodes from the TV series.
The film explores themes of peasant, hades, cartoon, villain, musical.
The tone is lighthearted and uplifting and emotional.